Rockwell Kent papers 4079547
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series VI:Book Illustration
  - Casanova de Seingalt, Giacomo
    - The memoirs...New York, Boni [c1932]
      - facing p.1176 pencil draft (Box 13)
      - facing p.1388 pencil draft (Box 13)
      - unused illus.: pencil draft (Box 13)
      - printed announcement (Box 13)
  - Chappell, George S.
    - A basket of poses. New York, Boni, 1924
      - p.11: pencil draft (Box 13)
      - p.19: pencil draft (Box 13)
      - p.50: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 13)
      - p.56: pencil draft (Box 13)
    - My northern exposure... by Walter E. Traprock. New York, Putnam, 1922
      - endpaper: printed copy in 5 colors (Box 13)
    - Rollo in society. New York, Putnam, 1922.
      - p.17: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - p.27: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - p.37: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - p.49: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - p.69: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - p.69: pencil draft (Box 13)
      - p.143: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - p.161: ink sketch (Box 13)
    - Sarah of the Saharah by Walter E. Traprock. New York, Putnam, 1923
      - book jacket: pencil draft (Box 13)
  - Chaucer, Geoffrey
    - Canterbury tales. New York, Covici-Friede, 1930
      - "The Franklin;" pencil draft (Box 13)
      - "The Knight;" ink draft (Box 13)
      - "The Knight;" pencil draft (Box 13)
      - "The Knight;" pencil draft (not used) (Box 13)
      - "The Knight," "The Miller," "The Reeve," "The Cook," The Lawyer," The Sailor;" pencil drafts (Box 13)
      - "The Lawyer;" pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 13)
      - "The Monk;" pencil draft (Box 13)
      - "The Pardoner;" pencil draft (Box 13)
      - "The Pardoner," "The Physician," "The Friar," The Squire;" pencil drafts (Box 13)
      - "The Prioress," "The Monk," "The Nun," "The Merchant," "The Clerk," "The Franklin," "The Wife of Bath," "The Parson," "The Ploughman," "The Miller," "The Manciple," "The Summoner;" pencil drafts (Box 13)
      - "The Summoner;" pencil draft (Box 13)
      - clipping illus. not used: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 13)
      - list of vignettes: a.ms., 3p. (Box 13)
      - medieval costumes: pencil sketches, 18p. (Box 13)
      - prospectus: printed leaflet (Box 13)
  - The Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Co.
    - Baltimore Telephone Book
      - cover: ink and pencil draft and pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 13)
  - Cleland, Thomas Maitland
    - The decorative work of T.M. Cleland... New York, The Pynson Printers, 1929.
      - frontspiece: oversize crayon draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
  - De Lima, Agnes
    - Our enemy the child. New York, New Republic [1925]:
      - prospectus: printed copy (Box 13)
  - Dostoievsky, Feodor
    - The brothers Karamazov. New York, Modern Library, 1937
      - cover-design-spine: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 13)
  - Dreams & derisions. [New York, the Pynson Printers], 1927
    - frontspiece: pencil drafts (Box 13)
    - p. 14 (Victrix): pencil draft (Box 13)
    - p. 15 [moonlight]: ink draft (Box 13)
    - p. 15 (Moonlight): pencil draft (Box 13)
    - p. 18 (Midnight): pencil and ink draft (Box 13)
    - p. 22 (Intermezzo): pencil draft (Box 13)
    - p. 33 (Revelation): pencil draft (Box 13)
    - p. 38: pencil draft (Box 13)
    - p. 46 (Minor measure): pencil draft (Box 13)
    - p. 57, p.67 & unused vignettes: pencil drafts (Box 13)
    - p. 72: pencil draft unused illus.: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 13)
    - proofs, 56p. (lacking pp. 21, 46, 47, 48, 50, 69, 72, 74, 86) (Box 13)
    - proofs, unused illus., 4p. (Box 13)
  - Fast, Howard
    - May Day-1947. [New York, United May Day Committee, 1947]
      - p.12: see: Titled drawings etc.: Glory, glory hallelujah.
  - France, Anatole
    - The revolt of the angels. New York, Modern Library [1928 À]
      - cover design-spine: pencil drafts (Box 13)
  - Freuchen, Peter
    - Eskimo. New York, Liveright, 1931
      - book jacket: charcoal & ink sketch (Box 13)
      - book jacket:pencil sketch clipping (Box 13)
  - Gisla saga Surssonar
    - The saga of Gisli. New York, Harcourt Brace [1936]
      - book jacket-spine: ink sketch (Box 13)
      - chapter 1: pencil draft chapter 2: (Box 13)
      - pencil draft chapter 3: pencil draft chapter 4: (Box 13)
      - pencil draft chapter 5: pencil draft chapter 6: (Box 13)
      - pencil draft chapter 7: pencil draft chapter 8: (Box 13)
      - pencil draft chapter 9: pencil draft chapter 10: (Box 13)
      - pencil draft chapter 11: pencil draft unused illus.: (Box 13)
      - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 13)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von
    - Faust. Norfolk, CT, New Directions, 1941
      - unused illus.: ink draft (Box 13)
      - unused illus.: ink sketch (Box 13)
  - Grinstead, Durward
    - Elva. New York, Covici-Friede, 1929
      - book jacket: pencil draft (Box 13)
  - Harris, Frank
    - My reminiscences as a cowboy. New York, Boni, 1930.
      - cover design: pencil draft (Box 13)
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Watch on the Rhine. New York [Privately published] 1942.
    - Cover design: 1 out of 5 copies printed by Leo Calapai at the Workshop Press (Glencoe IL) in, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Das Hildegartenbuch(?).
    - cover design: ink and pencil draft [re. Hildegarde HirschÀ] (Box 13)
  - Jarrett, Cora Hardy
    - Night over Fitch's Pond. Boston & New York, Houghton Mifflin, 1933
      - book jacket: pencil draft (Box 13)
  - Johnson, Marietta Louise Pierce
    - Youth in a world of men. New York, John Day [1929]
      - book jacket: pencil drafts (Box 13)
  - Jones, Dan Burne
    - The prints of Rockwell Kent: a catalogue raisonné. Chicago, The University of Chicago Press, 1975
      - cover illustration: window stand-up poster (signed by the author) (Box 13)
      - prospectus: printed copy (Box 13)
      - clipping (xerox copy) (Box 13)
  - Kent, Rockwell
    - A birthday book. New York, Random House, (not published), 1929
      - mock-up volume & 3 loose p. (Box 14)
    - A birthday book. New York, Random House, 1931
      - colophon-lettering: ink draft (Box 14)
      - colophon-lettering: pencil drafts (Box 14)
      - cover design: oversize blue lithography on silk and pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 14)
      - cover design (not used): pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 14)
      - cover title: ink lettering (Box 14)
      - cover title: pencil lettering (Box 14)
      - dedication illus.: ink sketches, 3p. (Box 14)
      - dedication illus.: pencil draft (Box 14)
      - half-title page: pencil draft (Box 14)
      - last page: ink sketch (Box 14)
      - last page: pencil drafts (Box 14)
      - misc., 1p. (Box 14)
      - mock-up pages, 4p. (Box 14)
      - p.12: tempera sketch (Box 14)
      - oversize pencil drafts (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - proofs, 7p. (Box 14)
      - proofs (4), 3p. (Box 14)
      - oversize proof text: galley proofs, 4p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - text: a.ms., 2p. (Box 14)
      - text: a.ms., 1p.:t.ms., 5p. (Box 14)
      - title-page lettering: pencil draft (Box 14)
      - See also: Stationery: Jones, Dan and Jacqui Book illus.: Kent: The golden chain
    - The bookplates and marks of Rockwell Kent. New York, Random House, 1929.
      - colophon: ink and pencil draft and printed copy (Box 14)
      - page proofs, 4p. (Box 14)
      - prospectus, 2 copies (Box 14)
      - prospectus-mock-up copy (Box 14)
    - Drawings by Rockwell Kent. New York, E. Weyhe, undated
      - announcement: printed copy (Box 14)
    - Greenland journal. New York, Obolensky [1962 1963]
      - book jacket: two-color ink mock-up, 2p. (Box 14)
      - [Dirty Deborah]: crayon sketch (Box 14)
      - [Dirty Deborah]: lithograph (Box 14)
      - [Good-by]: crayon sketch (Box 14)
      - [Kayaker]: crayon sketch (Box 14)
      - [Sophia]: crayon sketch (Box 14)
      - "Sermilik fiord," oversize pencil draft (Box 14)
      - Sophia: lithograph (Box 14)
      - untitled illus.: crayon sketches, 5p. (Box 14)
      - pencil drafts, 15p. (Box 14)
    - [Greenland journal.]Grenlandskii dnevnik. Moscow, Musl', 1969. (not published)
      - printed copy, 309p. (Box 14)
      - A Greenland letter. Chicago, The Lakeside Press, 1931
      - book jacket: pencil drafts (Box 14)
      - cover or title-page: oversize pencil draft (Box 14)
      - preface: proof, 3p. on one sheet (Box 14)
      - trial proof pages, 2p. (unrelated text) (Box 14)
      - See also: his book N by E
    - The golden chain. A fairy story. Privately printed, 1922 (Box ?)
      - a.ms. copy of book, dated 2 30 l. bound in velum with slipcase. (prototype for his: A birthday book.), March1922 (Box 1)
    - It is now eleven o'clock. N.p. [1928]
      - 9 watercolor and ink drawings (bound in one volume: dedicated to Olga Drexel Dahlgren). (Box 15)
    - It's me, O Lord. New York, Dodd Mead, 1955.
      - book jacket-lettering: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 15)
      - title-page illus.: pencil draft (Box 15)
      - title-page illus.: see also: Invitation: Goldman, Dr. and Mrs. Leo (Box 15)
      - title-page illus.: see also: Invitation: Chicago Council of American-Soviet Friendship (Box 15)
      - title-page illus.: see also: Poster: Chicago Council of American-Soviet... p.53: see: Book illus.: Powell, Lawrence C. (Box 15)
      - pencil draft, 1p. (Box 15)
      - announcement (mimeographed) (Box 15)
      - text: t.ms., 1036p. (with many corrections in his hand) (Box 15)
    - The Jewel: a romance of fairyland. Portland ME, The Baxter Society [c1989]
      - Prospectus: printed copy (Box 16)
    - Later bookplates and marks of Rockwell Kent. New York, The Pynson Printers, 193À (Box 16)
      - preliminary announcement, 1 printed copy (Box 16)
      - prospectus, printed leaflet (3 copies) (Box 16)
      - title-page illus.: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 16)
      - p.iii (dedication: ink sketches, 2p.) (Box 16)
      - colophon: proof: see: Bookplate: Harwell (Box 16)
    - The mad hermit... [Ausable Forks, NY, Asgaard Press, c1955] "New York, Emergency Civil Liberties Committee"
      - dummy copy: a.ms.s., 4p. (Box 16)
    - N by E. New York, Brewer & Warren, 1930
      - book jacket-mock up: 6p. (Box 16)
      - cover design: ink draft cover design: pencil drafts (Box 16)
      - cover design-mock up: black & gold ink sketch (Box 16)
      - title-page: ink draft (Box 16)
      - title-page: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - title-page: proof (with 2 photostats) (Box 16)
      - p.ix: see: Bookplate: Allen, Arthur S. Jr. (Box 16)
      - p.24-mock-up: pencil draft and printed copy "The bowsprit;" pencil draft (Box 16)
      - "Voyager:" proof (Box 16)
      - vignettes: proof (Box 16)
      - photostats, 6p. Part I: proofs, 54p. (Box 16)
      - Part II: proofs, 14p. (Box 16)
      - Part III: proofs, 15p. (Box 16)
      - Part III: proofs (photostats), 8p. (Box 16)
      - appendix: proofs, 10p. proof (not used), 1p. (Box 16)
      - prospectus-mock up copy (2) (Box 16)
      - prospectus-mock up copy: draft, 4p. (Box 16)
      - prospectus: printed copy (2) (Box 16)
      - prospectus-text: t.ms., 2p. (Box 16)
      - reviews, 2 clippings (Box 16)
    - N by E. New York, The Literary Guild, 1930.
      - book jacket: photostat (Box 16)
      - prospectus: printed leaflet (Box 16)
      - title-page: proofs, 2p. (Box 16)
    - N by E. New York, Putnam, 1930. (not published)
      - title-page: proof, 2p. (Box 16)
      - title-page: photostats, 2p. (Box 16)
    - N by E. New York, Random House, 1930.
      - cover design: ink and pencil draft (Box 16)
      - dedicatory leaf: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - dedicatory leaf: pencil sketch (Box 16)
      - dedicatory leaf: proof p.107: (Box 16)
      - ink and pencil draft (Box 16)
      - p.119: ink draft (Box 16)
      - "Close hauled;" see: Advertising: The Lakeside Press
      - "Hail and farewell;" pencil draft (Box 16)
      - "The lookout;" pencil draft (Box 16)
      - "Man at mast;" pencil draft (Box 16)
      - "Man at mast;" proofs, 4p. (Box 16)
      - "Masthead;" pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 16)
      - "Night watch;" ink and pencil draft (Box 16)
      - "Night watch;" photostat unused illus.: (Box 16)
      - ink sketches, 3p. oversize ink and pencil drafts (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - pencil drafts, 9p. (Box 16)
      - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. Part I: (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - Part I: proofs, 43p. (Box 16)
      - Part II: proofs, 15p. (Box 16)
      - Part III: proofs, 2p. (Box 16)
      - proof (not used) (Box 16)
      - see also: his A Greenland letter:
    - Newfoundland tragedy. (not published)
      - ink sketch (Box 16)
      - proof (Box 16)
      - photostat of proof, 4p. (Box 16)
    - A northern Christmas... New York, American Artists Group [c1941]
      - cover designs: pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 16)
      - title-page: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - title-page mock-up title-page text: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - p. [19]: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - page proofs, 21p. (Box 16)
      - sample page & note on type: pencil draft, 2p. (Box 16)
    - Of men and mountains. Ausable Forks, NY, Asgaard Press, 1959.
      - frontspiece: ink sketch (Box 16)
      - title-page illus.: ink sketch (Box 16)
      - title-page, dedicatory page, & p.5: pencil drafts (Box 16)
    - On earth peace... New York, American Artists Group [c1942] half-title page: pencil draft
      - title-page: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 16)
      - dedicatory leaf: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - p. [5] linecut initial: ink sketch (Box 16)
      - p. [5] linecut initial: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 16)
      - p. [6]: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - p. [7]: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 16)
      - p. [11] linecut initial: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - p. [12] linecut initial: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 16)
      - p. [12-13]: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - p. [14] linecut initial: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 16)
    - On earth peace ... New York, American Artists Group [c1942]
      - p. [17] linecut initial: pencil draft (Box 16)
      - linecut initial (not used): pencil draft (Box 16)
    - 100 famous paintings by Rockwell Kent. (À)
      - end-papers: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 16)
    - An open letter against the suppression of liberal thought... [Pittsburgh, American League for Peace and Democracy, 1939]
      - printed copy, 2 l. (Box 16)
    - Rockwell Kent: an anthology of his works. Ed. By Fridolf Johnson. New York, Knopf, 1981. Prospectus:
      - printed copy (Box 17)
    - Rockwellkentiana. New York, Harcourt Brace, 1933.
      - frontispiece: printed copy (Box 17)
      - title page: oversize pencil draft (Box 17)
      - title-page-lettering: ink and pencil draft (Box 17)
      - Binder's dummy, 10 l. in one volume (Box 17)
      - mailing label: printed copy (Box 17)
      - p. 1: proof (Box 17)
      - p. 5 (not used): proof (Box 17)
    - Salamina. New York, Harcourt Brace, 1935.
      - book jacket: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
      - title-page: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
      - p.3 initial letter: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.6 initial letter: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.9 initial letter: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - initial letter (not used): ink sketch (Box 17)
      - initial letter: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
      - p.41 initial letter: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.87 initial letter: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.93 initial letter: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.333 initial letter: ink draft (Box 17)
      - initial letter (not used): pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "David;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Found;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Full jacket;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Hunter;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Jorn;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Justina;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Kayaker;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Not Karen;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Pavia's wife;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - "Salamina;" pencil draft (Box 17)
      - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
      - text: a.ms., 1p. (draft) (Box 17)
      - clipping: prospectus, printed leaflet (Box 17)
    - The seven ages of man. New York, the author, 1918.
      - announcement: proof (Box 17)
    - This is my own. New York, Duell, Sloan and Pearce [1940]
      - book jacket: pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 17)
      - book jacket: pencil sketch book jacket: (Box 17)
      - watercolor sketch book jacket: oversize watercolor sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - contents page: oversize ink and pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - cover design: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
      - half-title page illus.: ink draft (Box 17)
      - title-page: ink sketch (not used) (Box 17)
      - title-page: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 17)
      - p.5: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.7 & p.9: ink sketches (Box 17)
      - p.11,51,93 & unused: pencil drafts (Box 17)
      - p.25: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.81: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 17)
      - p.89: ink sketch (Box 17)
      - p.89: pencil drafts (Box 17)
      - p.121, 129, 149 and unused: pencil drafts (Box 17)
      - p.137: ink sketch (Box 17)
      - p.137 and 277: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
      - p.165: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.171: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.179 and unused: ink draft (Box 17)
      - p.187, 197, 203, 217, 225 and unused: pencil drafts (Box 17)
      - p.211: pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 17)
      - p.211: pencil sketch and 293: pencil drafts and 245: pencil drafts (Box 17)
      - p.249, 285, 303 and unused: pencil drafts (Box 17)
      - p.255: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.265: pencil draft (Box 17)
      - p.275: pencil draft (Box 17)
    - p.293: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
    - p.329,351 and unused: pencil drafts (Box 17)
    - p.341: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
    - p.385: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
    - p.391: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
    - unused illus.: ink sketches, 2p. (Box 17)
    - unused illus.: pencil drafts, 10p. (Box 17)
    - page lay-out, 1p. (Box 17)
    - prospectus: printed leaflet (Box 17)
    - misc. notes, etc., 6p. (Box 17)
    - clippings, 2p. (Box 17)
  - To thee ! [New York, 1946]
    - cover design: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
    - frontspiece: proof (Box 17)
    - frontspiece (not used): ink sketch, 2p. (Box 17)
    - dedicatory page-text: a.ms., 1p. (Box 17)
    - p.48: pencil and ink draft (Box 17)
    - p.48: pencil draft p.56: (Box 17)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 17)
    - p.58: pencil tracing from photograph (Box 17)
    - colophon illus.: proof colophon text: (Box 17)
    - 2 a.ms.s. unbound copy, 59p. in 32 l. (Box 17)
    - misc. (Box 17)
  - Voyaging... New York, Putnam, 1924.
    - box label (reduced size): proof (Box 19)
    - dedicatory page illus.: see: Christmas card: 1914-Mrs. Rockwell Kent (Box 18)
    - chapter heads: 26 ink drawings bound in 1 vol. (Box 18)
    - p.17 [map]: oversize ink and wash sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - p.35 [The Kathleen of New York]: proof (Box 19)
    - p.39: [map] ink sketch (Box 19)
    - 74 [Bridge Across Azapardo River]: pencil drawing for woodcut (Box 18)
    - p.76 [chapter head]: ink sketch (Box 19)
    - p.148: See: Inescort, Frieda, a.l.s. to Rockwell Kent
    - unused illus.: ink sketches & pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 19)
    - text: a.ms., 14p. (drafts) (Box 19)
    - text: a.ms. & t.ms., 209p. (drafts & notes) (Box 18)
    - The Magellan Times, 31 January 1923. p.5-8, reprinted as p.183-184 of Voyaging (Box 19)
    - reviews, 5p. (photostats) (Box 19)
    - clippings, 4p. (Box 19)
  - What is an American À [Los Angeles, Plantin Press, 1936] frontspiece: see: Titles drawings, etc.:August twenty-third:
  - Wilderness. New York, Putnam, 1920.
    - book jacket: ink and pencil drafts (Box 19)
    - book jacket: ink draft (Box 19)
    - book jacket: ink sketch (Box 19)
    - book jacket: oversize proof (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - dedication: pencil draft (Box 19)
    - end-paper: proof (Box 19)
    - frontspiece: proof (Box 19)
    - frontspiece, p.65 and 67: proof (Box 19)
    - title-page: ink draft (Box 19)
    - p.xi: proof (Box 19)
    - p.xi-xii-text: a.ms., 2p. (draft) (Box 19)
    - p.1: proof (Box 19)
    - p.1-2-text: a.ms., 2p. (draft) (Box 19)
    - p.3: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.6-9-text: a.ms., 2p. (draft) (Box 19)
    - p.7: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.13: proof, 2p. (Box 19)
    - p.17: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.21: proof, 13p. (Box 19)
    - p.25: proof, 5p. (Box 19)
    - p.29: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.29 & 162: proof (Box 19)
    - p.33: proof, 2p. (one page torn in halves) (Box 19)
    - p.37: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.37 and 67: proof (Box 19)
    - p.41 and 102: proof (Box 19)
    - p.43: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.47: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.51: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.57: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.61: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.65: proof (Box 19)
    - p.69: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.73: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.75-79-text: a.ms., 3p. (draft) (Box 19)
    - p.77: proof, 2p. (Box 19)
    - p.80-83-text: a.ms., 2p. (draft) (Box 19)
    - p.81: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.91: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.95: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.105: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.109: ink draft (Box 19)
    - p.109 and 134: proof (Box 19)
    - p.111: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.115: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.119: proof, 6p. "Woman" (Box 19)
    - p.125: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.129: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.137: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.141: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.147: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.155: proof, 2p. (Box 19)
    - p.159: proof (Box 19)
    - p.165: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.169: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.173: proof, 2p. (Box 19)
    - p.177: proof (Box 19)
    - p.182: proof (Box 19)
    - p.185: proof, 2p. (Box 19)
    - p.189: proof (Box 19)
    - p.193: proof (Box 19)
    - p.197: proof, 2p. (Box 19)
    - p.203: proof, 3p. (Box 19)
    - p.207: proof, 4p. (Box 19)
    - p.211: proof (Box 19)
    - p.217-vignette: ink draft "Fox Island from the air" (Box 19)
    - (unused illus.): pencil and ink draft "Olson" (Box 19)
    - (unused illus.): pencil sketch "Young Rockwell with his porcupine" (unused illus.): pencil draft (Box 19)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 19)
    - misc. photostats, 5p. (Box 19)
    - prospectus: (Box 19)
    - printed leaflet (Box 19)
    - clippings, 2p. (Box 19)
  - Linklater, Eric
    - The men of Ness. New York, Farrar & Rinehart [c1933]
      - title-page: red and black ink lettering (Box 20)
  - Litchfield, P.W.
    - Autumn leaves. Akron, Ohio, Goodyear Tire & Rubber Co., 1945.
      - title-page: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 20)
      - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 20)
  - Lovise Honor: a melody (1906-1917). N.p., undated
    - cover design: ink and pencil draft (Box 20)
  - Marley, Harold
    - untitled. N.p., undated
      - frontspiece: pencil drafts (Box 20)
  - May Day. [New York, United May Day Committee, 1941]
    - cover design: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 20)
    - cover design: oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - printed pamphlet, 8p. (Box 20)
  - Medals of honor. N.p., undated
    - cover design: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 20)
  - Melville, Herman
    - Moby Dick. Chicago, The Lakeside Press, 1930.
      - cover design: pencil draft (Box 20)
      - cover design: oversize pencil drafts, 4p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - title-page vignette, vol.2: pencil draft (Box 20)
      - title-page vignette, vol.3: pencil draft (Box 20)
      - colophon: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 20)
      - vignettes (photostats of proofs), 27p. (Box 20)
      - mock-ups, paper samples, proofs, etc., 63 items (Box 20)
      - sample pages, 1 item (Box 20)
      - Un-used illustrations-article by Dan Burne Jones: "Moby Dick: the un-used illustrations", p. 5-10 of Extracts/ an occasional newsletter, No. 30, printed copy, 7p., May 1977 (Box 20)
    - Moby Dick. New York, Random House, 1930.
      - cover design: pencil drafts, 13p. (Box 20)
      - title-page: pencil and ink draft (Box 20)
      - p.viii & 57: pencil and ink drafts (Box 20)
      - p.58 & 230: pencil drafts (Box 20)
      - p.79 and 84: pencil drafts (Box 20)
      - p.81: pencil draft (Box 20)
      - p.94 and 117 and unused: pencil drafts (Box 20)